Matthew Alunni

https://matthewalunni.github.io/portfolio/ https://github.com/matthewalunni/

Summary

IT professional and Engineering Design student with 5+ years' experience developing web, mobile, and desktop solutions for diverse industry clients. Highly instrumental in all phases of the SDLC, with expertise in data structures and algorithms.

EDUCATION

Master of Engineering Design in Product Design; GPA: 4.00

McMaster University

Email: matthew.alunni@gmail.com

Mobile: +1-289-442-4004

Coursework: Industrial Automation, IoT, Rapid Prototyping, Advanced Robotics and Automation

Bachelor of Computing and Business

Brock University

Coursework: Data Structures and Algorithms, Databases, AI, OOP, Software Engineering, Networking

EXPERIENCE

Deloitte Toronto, ON

Software Developer

Jan. 2022 - Present

- Ad Portal: Worked with project managers to help build a single-page web application using NextJS and TypeScript to introduce ad revenue to all Loblaws e-commerce stores.
- Automation: Configured CI/CD pipelines so that each commit a developer makes will go through a standard lint, test, build and release process in GitLab CI.
- User Interface: Used React with Material UI to create custom UI components following Figma mockups showing graphs, tables, and forms.
- Code Reviews: Conducted and received code reviews to ensure the work delivered by the team is of the highest quality.

RBC Toronto, ON

Software Developer

April 2019 - Sept. 2021

- Ticketing Kanban: Worked in an agile environment creating Python/Django web applications using a SQL Server database on the backend to create a ticketing system to manage the work of cybersecurity consultants.
- Automation: Worked with and designed RESTful APIs to automate business processes saving thousands of hours for the cybersecurity consulting team.
- Dashboards: Used React with Bootstrap and Axios to follow mockups in creating a front-end for a ticketing system, showing graphs, statistics, and graphics.
- Automation: Independently created C# desktop applications to automate project intake by using analytical skills to save time for members of the cybersecurity department
- Employee Management System: Added utility by creating a .NET application that integrated with tools such as ActiveDirectory to provide convenience for RBC employees.

Campari Canada

Toronto, ON

Software Developer

July 2018 - Dec. 2018

- Intranet Site: Independently built Campari Canada's intranet site by using Django with a PostGres database, deployed with Heroku to allow Campari to properly organize their internal resources.
- Dashboards: Created responsive dashboards using React to allow for a more fluid experience, integrating internal and external Campari employee resources.
- Data Collection and Storage: Integrated a Python backend with a PostGres database to help efficiently store, edit, and monitor employee data.

Projects

• TowerGrow: A 3D printed IoT desktop hydroponic garden controlled through a React Native mobile application

Programming Skills

• HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material UI, TypeScript, React, Node.js, Python, Django, React Native, Git, SQL Server, PostGres, Linux, Heroku, Docker, CAD, Cura, Fusion360